ظآزShrugging off past burdensظآز
ظآزBeneath the mask, who am I?ظآز
ظآزRelease and find wider shoresظآز
ظآزLove's a riddle, and rain pours heavyظآز
ظآزCrossed paths, now downward fallظآز
ظآزFrom dust arises starlight's sparkظآز
ظآزTearing through
the night's dense blockadeظآز
ظآزHeart's flame illuminates all solitudeظآز
ظآزLet time's sails drift endlesslyظآز
ظآزThrough wandering exileظآز
ظآزBreaking free from the cocoon,
I start anewظآز
ظآزMoon as song, life as flameظآز
ظآزNameless heart clings fiercelyظآز
ظآزLet meظآز
ظآزCharge toward the next raging riverظآز
ظآزMoon darts, snow fallsظآز
ظآزWe tread rugged paths to reuniteظآز
ظآزHands held tightظآز
ظآزWe forever live for love's sakeظآز
ظآزShadow's spear burns fiercelyظآز
=Legend of The Female General=
=Episode 36=
It is
the war drums being beaten.
Commander.
Crisis at the border.
Wutuo attacks Mingshui
and Huayuan simultaneously.
No time to waste. Go to the palace now.
(Longtai Hall)
Wutuo actually broke the peace treaty
and invaded us again.
That's so unscrupulous!
Xiao Jue.
You lead troops to Mingshui.
This time, we must teach Wutuo a lesson
and ensure
they never dare invade us again.
As you command.
He Yan.
I order you to lead the Fuyue Army
and defend Rundu with Li Kuang
to guard against Wutuo's raids.
Your Majesty.
There's no battle in Rundu.
Yet Wutuo's forces
are approaching Huayuan.
It's threatening.
There's no current conflict,
but Wutuo is full of tricks.
We must be alert.
As for Huayuan,
I've sent Yan He there,
with Chu Zhao as military supervisor
to assist.
Yes, understood.
His Majesty wants me to guard Rundu,
but Li Kuang is there.
Why send me too?
In my opinion,
His Majesty still distrusts us.
An emperor's balance of power
is an age-old strategy.
But there's wisdom
in this arrangement.
Rundu lies between Huayuan and Mingshui.
It allows quick support to both cities.
Promise me
you'll return safely.
Take Wang Ba's team
to Rundu with you.
There's no battle there.
Keep them with you.
I have Feinu and Shen Han.
With them guarding you,
I'll feel assured.
Okay.
Miss He.
Congratulations.
You've won imperial favor
and secured the supervisor position.
A little tiger is roaring.
What's wrong?
The baby kicked me.
Behave yourself,
or I'll punish you when I return.
Don't threaten our baby.
Yan He.
This time,
let me go with you.
I went along with troops before.
This is different!
You're pregnant now.
The due date is still weeks away.
Besides,
as a general's wife,
I can endure hardships.
Fine.
I'll stay by your side
and see the birth of our baby.
I'll be the best father in the capital.
(Xiao Mansion)
You guys
focus on the war.
My wife and I will handle home affairs.
Miss He.
May you return safely.
(Xiao Mansion)
(Rundu City)
General He, time to eat.
General He.
I heard you returned
to write battle reports.
Haven't started yet?
Nothing to report.
Wutuo forces
continue assaults on Huayuan
and Mingshui,
while Rundu remains peaceful.
General.
General! Emergency!
New battle report.
Wutuo sent reinforcements
to attack Huayuan.
General Yan has fought nonstop
for two days.
- Mai.
- Yes.
You go tell Li Kuang
that I'll leave 5,000 soldiers
to defend the city.
The rest will reinforce Huayuan with me.
- Yes.
(He)
I heard you all rushed here
from Rundu
and repelled enemies with Yan He.
I've prepared a banquet
to honor your victory.
- Great.
Xiu, I'm back.
He has returned.
Madam.
What's wrong?
Careful, Madam.
What's happening?
Someone!
Madam is going into labor.
- General Yan!
- General!
Medic!
Don't.
Don't tell Xiu.
She's pregnant.
Don't alarm her.
Hang in there!
The medic is coming.
Promise me.
Xiu.
I'm sorry.
Take a deep breath and push!
Deep breath, Madam.
Keep pushing!
Push harder!
Push! Keep pushing!
Breathe in.
Madam.
Y-Yan He...
Push, Madam!
Push! Hold your breath!
Hold it! Keep holding!
Hold your breath!
Almost done!
Yan He
is still mopping up remaining enemies
behind the lines.
He'll return later.
Push harder, Madam!
Hold your breath and push!
That's it!
Hold and push!
It's born!
Madam!
Congratulations!
It's a girl!
She's born, Madam!
She's beautiful!
Careful.
It's Muxia.
Muxia?
Yan He chose this name.
Liangjiang for a boy,
Muxia for a girl.
Muxia,
your father is a great hero.
Muxia, you will grow up
to carry on your father's legacy.
Muxia
will become
a good general
like her father.
So adorable.
Muxia.
(Yan)
Are Mrs. Yan and the child safe?
Safe?
Yes,
they're safe.
But the child lost her father at birth.
Father and daughter
never even met.
This battle could have ended sooner
with fewer casualties.
All because of your loyal advice,
His Majesty
feared our concentrated military power,
ordering me
to station the Fuyue Army in Rundu,
scattering our forces.
So, we couldn't deliver
a decisive blow to Wutuo.
Is this the outcome
you wanted,
Mr. Chu?
You don't deserve to get wasted.
Stay sober and atone for this.
This is
to honor the fallen soldiers.
(Zilan, you're smart and diligent.)
You will earn scholarly honors.
When you grow up,
you'll become a good
and respectable official.
(Then no one will
dare bully you anymore.)
Mother.
Don't cry, Zilan.
I'm just tired.
My poor son.
(Mother, I'll take you away
from the Chu family.)
We don't have to endure their insult.
Mother.
Mother!
(I only fear)
you'll end up alone.
From now on,
stop pushing yourself so hard.
Spare yourself.
ظآزUpon towering fortress wallsظآز
ظآزBrooding over lamented pastsظآز
ظآزWhere shall light be foundظآز
ظآزOnceظآز
ظآزI had an unbreakable faithظآز
You know what?
You are
becoming like Xu Jingfu.
ظآزResent old dreams like drifting cloudsظآز
ظآزHeartacheظآز
ظآزResenting the lonely yearsظآز
I believed
I upheld moral principles,
unlike scum like Xu Jingfu.
Now,
stubbornness blinded me.
Endless warfare,
widespread suffering,
families torn apart,
all because of me.
If the ruler
and ministers had been united,
with generals defending Wei,
Wutuo would've never invaded!
I was wrong.
General He.
Urgent news!
It's Mingshui.
After losing in Huayuan,
Wutuo sent more troops to Mingshui.
Their troops from Huayuan
are already advancing there.
The Xiao Army can't
resist much longer with weak forces.
We must reinforce them!
Mr. Jiang, you stay here.
Assist General Yan's deputy
in defending Huayuan.
Understood!
Xiao Jue!
Surrender now,
and I'll kindly spare your life.
Don't end up dead in Mingshui
like Xiao Zhongwu!
Soldiers of Wei
will never surrender!
- Never surrender!
Charge!
- Charge!
ظآزMoon as song, life as flameظآز
ظآزNameless heart clings fiercelyظآز
ظآزCharge toward the next raging riverظآز
ظآزMoon darts, snow fallsظآز
ظآزWe tread rugged paths to reuniteظآز
ظآزHolding hands tight,
we make a commitmentظآز
ظآزI can't forget or break freeظآز
ظآزShatter all shacklesظآز
ظآزNo matter what, I can't let you goظآز
ظآزTearing through
the night's dense blockadeظآز
ظآزHeart's flame illuminates all solitudeظآز
ظآزLet time's sails drift through,
wandering aroundظآز
ظآزBreaking free from the cocoon,
I start anewظآز
ظآزMoon as song, life as flameظآز
ظآزFearless heart remains silentظآز
ظآزLet me repeat destiny's cycleظآز
ظآزI laughed it offظآز
ظآزThe galaxy still shines brightlyظآز
ظآزRemember to always live for loveظآز
ظآزHold a spearظآز
ظآزAnd fightظآز
ظآزNever stopظآز
ظآزMove onظآز
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزUnveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstreamظآز
ظآزThe resonance of courage
rings loud and clearظآز
ظآزIt's the boldness
that defines existenceظآز
ظآزSoaring across the world's expanseظآز
- We won!
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزUnveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstreamظآز
ظآزThe resonance of courage
rings loud and clearظآز
ظآزIt's the boldness
that defines existenceظآز
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزBurying frailty,
embracing life through deathظآز
ظآزYou'll meet gazes where storms brewظآز
ظآزWith our unwavering true love,
brave the world with meظآز
Chu Zhao,
Vice Director of the Secretariat,
prioritized personal desires
and sowed discord repeatedly,
making the military strength divided,
allowing Wutuo's invasion.
War reignited,
causing immense suffering.
He is hereby dismissed
and exiled to the borderlands
and will never return.
By Imperial Decree.
Thanks for your hard work.
Rise, please.
Thank you.
Your Majesty.
Amidst urgent warfare,
I prioritized military necessity,
leaving Rundu
without permission.
This defied imperial orders.
I deserve punishment.
Your Majesty.
General Feihong
contributed to the victory.
She committed no crime.
Good judgment.
Xiao Jue, you also
contributed to the victory.
Rewards for you both
have been sent to your mansions.
Well,
you may leave.
- Thank you.
Yan He.
Actually,
when I married you,
I knew
this day might come.
But I never expected
that it'd happen so soon.
But don't worry.
Since I've married you,
I'll never regret it.
No matter how difficult,
I'll live on resolutely
and raise our child well.
Muxia.
May you grow up healthy.
Your father
will surely watch over you.
Careful!
Slow down!
Soldiers fight on the battlefield
for this peaceful life.
If Yan He
could see this,
he might rest in peace.
Sadly,
he and Chengxiu
are already separated by death.
Huaijin,
we promised each other
to face the future
and cherish every single day.
Even if eventually...
Even if one of us dies in battle,
the other one must keep living
courageously
to see our nation's splendor and peace.
(General Feihong's Mansion)
This road feels too short.
If only we could walk longer together.
We have time.
I'll always stay with you.
We live together when we're alive.
After death, we'll be
buried together.
I'll give you a spot beside me.
Who asked you to do that?
I'm the renowned General Feihong!
Well,
you keep a spot for me?
You wish.
(General Feihong's Mansion)
Excuse me,
if I may interject?
Stop talking
about the spot.
An imperial edict arrived.
Come and take it.
(General Feihong's Mansion)
By Heaven's Mandate,
Xiao Jue, General Fengyun,
is accomplished, loyal, and valiant.
He Yan, General Feihong,
is a heroine
of unmatched talent and brilliance.
Both are loyal generals
and pillars of Wei.
I hereby grant you marriage.
May you two stay together happily
and guard borders and people together.
That's all!
- Thank you.
(One month later)
(General Feihong's Mansion)
So the bride is the first
female general.
Truly remarkable!
Look, how magnificent!
- Here they are!
(Prosperity)
Careful.
(Wedding Procession)
(Xiao Mansion)
It's a wedding ceremony
of two families.
A man and a woman are getting married
as promised.
ظآزConstant yearningظآز
ظآزStill vivid as our first meetingظآز
ظآزEndless gazingظآز
ظآزStep by step, falling deeperظآز
ظآزHow to untangle this loveظآز
ظآزBuried deep within dreamsظآز
ظآزMy heart, unyielding as stone,
remains trueظآز
ظآزAwaiting the crescent moon's
reflection in your heartظآز
ظآزSplendor fades from your eyesظآز
ظآزCrimson threads entwine like rings,
binding our first vowظآز
ظآزTime lingers as you and I share
overlapping palm linesظآز
(The last secret.)
I love the moon.
Yet the moon doesn't know.
Now,
the moon is yours.
ظآزIn the vast world,
I searched for yearsظآز
ظآزShadows hustle. Scenes reappearظآز
ظآزWhat is there to fearظآز
ظآزWe'll weather storms togetherظآز
ظآزThrough endless dawns and dusks,
to eternityظآز
ظآزAwaiting the crescent moon's
reflection in your heartظآز
ظآزSplendor fades from your eyesظآز
ظآزCrimson threads entwine like rings,
binding our first vowظآز
ظآزTime lingers as you and I share
overlapping palm linesظآز
ظآزZither and harp
accompany our dancing dreamsظآز
Yan,
I'm afraid you feel bored,
so I came to chat.
Yan?
Taotao,
have you seen Huaijin?
Isn't he toasting guests right now?
I've searched.
Didn't find him.
They say
the moonlight over Mount Cuiwang
is peerless.
Let's watch it tonight.
Peerless?
I doubt it.
ظآزWalking through the crowd,
without asking about the futureظآز
It seems
the peerless moon
is feeling jealous.
ظآزI failed to let it go and kept lookingظآز
ظآزLonging continues,
as feelings are changingظآز
ظآزJust to see you turn aroundظآز
The peerless moon
is yours now.
ظآزJust to tread the snow you describedظآز
ظآزThe more fate intertwines intensely,
the further we drift apartظآز
ظآزIt's hard to sever love or hatredظآز
Xiao Jue.
Tell me,
in 10 years, 20 years,
even 50 years from now,
how will the moon differ from tonight's?
I don't know.
I wonder what the moon
will be like decades from now,
compared to
the present one.
I'm also curious.
So,
let's watch together.
(The End)
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزUnveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstreamظآز
ظآزThe resonance of courage
rings loud and clearظآز
ظآزIt's the boldness
that defines existenceظآز
ظآزI've seen the mountainsظآز
ظآزAnd trodden through iceظآز
ظآزDay after day, I venture aloneظآز
ظآزDestiny is my creedظآز
ظآزIdeals surge beneath the surfaceظآز
ظآزIgniting the flame against the windsظآز
ظآزA restless yearning in my soulظآز
ظآزGazing through the mireظآز
ظآزWho cares about this boundless voidظآز
ظآزCharge ahead with blazing fervorظآز
ظآزStubbornly fighting with my lifeظآز
ظآزSoaring across the world's expanseظآز
ظآزThere must always be a longingظآز
ظآزDisregard the wounds to seek the lightظآز
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزUnveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstreamظآز
ظآزThe resonance of courage
rings loud and clearظآز
ظآزIt's the boldness
that defines existenceظآز
ظآزChasing the light within my heartظآز
ظآزBurying frailty,
embracing life through deathظآز
ظآزYou'll meet gazes where storms brewظآز
ظآزWith our unwavering true love,
brave the world with meظآز
ظآزSoaring across the world's expanseظآز
ظآزThere must always be a longingظآز
ظآزDisregard the wounds to seek the lightظآز
ظآزLight shines upon my heartظآز
ظآزUnveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstreamظآز
ظآزThe resonance of courage
rings loud and clearظآز
ظآزIt's the boldness
that defines existenceظآز
ظآزChasing the light within my heartظآز
ظآزBurying frailty,
embracing life through deathظآز
ظآزYou'll meet gazes where storms brewظآز
ظآزWith our unwavering true love,
brave the world with meظآز